<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-29T12:40:46-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Hussain Dhanani</title><subtitle>Musings on product, design, leadership, and teams.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Shopify Unite Conference Recap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/29/shopify-unite-recap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shopify Unite Conference Recap" /><published>2017-04-29T12:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-04-29T12:30:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/29/shopify-unite-recap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/29/shopify-unite-recap.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been over a week since I flew down to beautiful San Francisco to attend Shopify Unite - Shopify’s annual conference for partners that build apps for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.shopify.com/&quot;&gt;Shopify App Store&lt;/a&gt;.  Here is my recap of how the conference went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shopify-unite-partner-documentary&quot;&gt;Shopify Unite Partner Documentary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk about telling a compelling story to ignite the whole audience by speaking to how anyone can change their entire life from just a single idea. Shopify’s partner documentary kicked off the conference, and it did an incredible job at setting the tone for the next two days.  As a newcomer to the Shopify partner network I was inspired by how any one of us could empower merchants to make their businesses a success.  It also hit notes on the entrepreneurial spirit that Shopify speaks to and enables through their platform.  This really did a number on me.  Take a look at the documentary video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6HOVX0wQOFY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-announcements&quot;&gt;Product Announcements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the documentary was over and the keynote address was completed, it was on to the many product announcements.  I am not going to go into detail of each announcement because I want to talk about the nature of the announcements and what Shopify did really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the thirty or so announcements (some massive and some minor) had a particular style to them that resonated with me.  Each announcement started with a background to set the context. It then went into the problem that arose from the background.  Next, the announcement itself, which was the solution to the problem.  Finally, it concluded with a sneak peak or a live demo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I really enjoyed was that for some of the major announcements, the Shopify individuals went as far as reporting on how beta-testing was going.  I believe every single one of the announcements made some kind of mention towards beta-testing.  I loved this because it definitely showed me how user-centric Shopify is as a Product company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are curious to learn about the major announcements, head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shopify.com/blog/everything-we-announced-at-unite-2017&quot;&gt;Shopify’s Blog&lt;/a&gt; and have a read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;individual-sessions&quot;&gt;Individual Sessions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the major product announcements, the conference officially kicked off.  There were 3 tracks and each track had sessions until about 5pm on the first day.  The focus of the sessions was to give attendees a closer look at all of the features that were announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great time watching my former colleague Kyle Peatt co-host a session on &lt;a href=&quot;https://polaris.shopify.com/&quot;&gt;Shopify Polaris&lt;/a&gt;, a unified design system that both Shopify and its partners can use to create seamless experiences for Shopify merchants.  Partners seemed to really take to having their apps use the same design systems as Shopify.  It was also great to see Shopify put their weight behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.github.io/react/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt;, a JavaScript library for building UI.  React has been around for quite some time now and the developer community is very active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;san-francisco-goes-dark&quot;&gt;San Francisco Goes Dark&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the second day of the conference, while walking into a coffee shop in the Russian Hill district, the shop completely lost power.  Thinking it was due to the construction directly outside, we went to another place to grab a coffee and a quick breakfast.  Unbeknownst to us the power was out for the entire city north of Market St.  My phone ended up buzzing and I had a push notification letting me know that the conference centre was without power.  Breakfast was still being served there, so my colleague and I made our way to the Fort Mason Center to get coffee and food into our bellies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arriving there was already a large group of attendees enjoying the sunshine and chatting away while eating delicious baked goods and hot coffee.  We all ended up hanging out until about noon, when lunch was being served.  At this time another announcement was made that there would be power in one of the tents of the conference (thanks to a backup generator) and the rest of the sessions for the day would be recorded and passed on to each attendee after the conference.  Best part was, no one seemed to mind.  This was a great opportunity to meet other developers and talk to them about their stories and what they are trying to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was amazing to see that there were startups, as well as established brands, all thriving from building apps that live in the Shopify App Store.  The full scale of the Shopify App Store, similar to Apple’s own App Store, hit me that afternoon.  It was an incredible feeling.  It took me back to the first day, at the start of the conference, when the partner documentary was shown.  These individuals really were enabling entrepreneurs to become more successful, by providing apps that were relevant to their business models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-end&quot;&gt;The End&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shopify put on an amazing event last week.  As an attendee, I appreciated the incredible amount of detail that went into the planning and execution.  I especially enjoyed the individual product announcements that took place on the first day.  The partner documentary was the biggest winner of the conference, and I am sure most developers felt the same way.  I hope I am privileged again to attend next year when the conference is held in Toronto, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s been over a week since I flew down to beautiful San Francisco to attend Shopify Unite - Shopify’s annual conference for partners that build apps for the Shopify App Store. Here is my recap of how the conference went.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I Learned About Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion This Week</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/16/what-I-learned-about-diversity-and-inclusion-this-week.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I Learned About Diversity &amp; Inclusion This Week" /><published>2017-04-16T21:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-04-16T21:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/16/what-I-learned-about-diversity-and-inclusion-this-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/16/what-I-learned-about-diversity-and-inclusion-this-week.html">&lt;p&gt;Diversity and inclusion, as a topic, has been very popular in the media lately.  From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/28/technology/tech-roundup-improving-ubers-diversity-and-culture.html&quot;&gt;Uber’s ongoing struggles with diversity and culture&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/04/08/523129221/google-accused-of-underpaying-female-employees&quot;&gt;Google being accused of underpaying women employees&lt;/a&gt;, you can’t go a week without reading something in the news around these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why is it important to me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone that is considered an ethnic minority, I can see first hand the struggles of creating a product organization that is truly diverse.  Being in tech also means I have witnessed the struggles of tech startups to create a truly inclusive culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to be able to create an open and safe space for others to talk about these struggles and come up with strategies to tackle an issue that’s finally getting the level of attention it deserves.  I do plan on writing a future article on my observations about potential blockers that prevent organizations from being truly diverse and inclusive; but for now I want to do a quick recap of what I’ve come across over the past week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stephanie-lampkins-blendoorcom&quot;&gt;Stephanie Lampkin’s Blendoor.com&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a goal of reporting on diversity without the influence of unconscious bias, Stephanie created an app last year to report on tech companies workforce makeup.  The app rates companies based on demographics of leadership, retention stats, recruiting practices, bias, and social impact initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An initiative like Blendoor is seriously kick ass.  I am pretty amazed at which companies score higher than others.  Slack is scored lower than Microsoft.  Netflix is scored lower than HP.  I was intrigued that HP has the highest rank out of all scored companies.  There are a lot of companies that don’t have a score yet, and it will be cool to see how this evolves over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blendoor.com/&quot;&gt;Blendoor.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;style--class-vancouver&quot;&gt;Style &amp;amp; Class Vancouver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend and co-worker of mine invited me to attend Style &amp;amp; Class on Wednesday April 12th.  The topic of the Meetup was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/styleandclass/events/238961461/&quot;&gt;Equality &amp;amp; Ideal Futures in Technology&lt;/a&gt;.  I had the honor of hearing Ashley Victoria’s presentation on sexism in the workplace.  From her real-life examples, it’s bewildering to hear how some men view women at work.  How men can behave towards women at work, or at a conference, or at a holiday party.  I was really grateful to hear these stories and to reaffirm, once again, that we can all be an ally to our co-workers and friends - no matter what their makeup or background is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a new week begins, as we see more and more articles in the news around diversity and inclusion, I encourage everyone to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a safe and open environment to discuss these issues at work and at home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to be mindful of what we say and how that might impact how others are viewed or treated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to look for ways to be an ally to those around you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Diversity and inclusion, as a topic, has been very popular in the media lately. From Uber’s ongoing struggles with diversity and culture, and Google being accused of underpaying women employees, you can’t go a week without reading something in the news around these issues.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to My Blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/08/welcome-to-my-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to My Blog!" /><published>2017-04-08T22:26:30-07:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T22:26:30-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/08/welcome-to-my-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/08/welcome-to-my-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;After hundreds of conversations, countless articles read, and numerous books consumed, I am really excited to finally start this blog.  My goal is very simple: Share my ideas about the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the majority of that world is working for a product company.  I spend an incredible amount of time working for a company I believe is making a difference in the world.  And that is exciting.  Not just for me but for any of you that are reading this excuse for a blog (really I can joke about it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy the posts I write and I hope they initiate a discussion with those around you (unless you want to rant at me, which is why I have shared my twitter and github profiles in the footer).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After hundreds of conversations, countless articles read, and numerous books consumed, I am really excited to finally start this blog. My goal is very simple: Share my ideas about the world around me.</summary></entry></feed>