<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-16T20:48:17-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Hussain Dhanani</title><subtitle>Musings on product, design, leadership, and teams.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to My Blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/08/welcome-to-my-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to My Blog!" /><published>2017-04-08T22:26:30-07:00</published><updated>2017-04-08T22:26:30-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/08/welcome-to-my-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/08/welcome-to-my-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;After hundreds of conversations, countless articles read, and numerous books consumed, I am really excited to finally start this blog.  My goal is very simple: Share my ideas about the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the majority of that world is working for a product company.  I spend an incredible amount of time working for a company I believe is making a difference in the world.  And that is exciting.  Not just for me but for any of you that are reading this excuse for a blog (really I can joke about it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy the posts I write and I hope they initiate a discussion with those around you (unless you want to rant at me, which is why I have shared my twitter and github profiles in the footer).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After hundreds of conversations, countless articles read, and numerous books consumed, I am really excited to finally start this blog. My goal is very simple: Share my ideas about the world around me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I Learned About Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion This Week</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/0016/04/30/what-I-learned-about-diversity-and-inclusion-this-week.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I Learned About Diversity &amp; Inclusion This Week" /><published>0016-04-30T21:26:30-08:00</published><updated>0016-04-30T21:26:30-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/0016/04/30/what-I-learned-about-diversity-and-inclusion-this-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/0016/04/30/what-I-learned-about-diversity-and-inclusion-this-week.html">&lt;p&gt;Diversity and inclusion, as a topic, has been very popular in the media lately.  From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/28/technology/tech-roundup-improving-ubers-diversity-and-culture.html&quot;&gt;Uber’s ongoing struggles with diversity and culture&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/04/08/523129221/google-accused-of-underpaying-female-employees&quot;&gt;Google being accused of underpaying women employees&lt;/a&gt;, you can’t go a week without reading something in the news around these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why is it important to me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone that is considered an ethnic minority, I can see first hand the struggles of creating a product organization that is truly diverse.  Being in tech also means I have witnessed the struggles of tech startups to create a truly inclusive culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to be able to create an open and safe space for others to talk about these struggles and come up with strategies to tackle an issue that’s finally getting the level of attention it deserves.  I do plan on writing a future article on my observations about potential blockers that prevent organizations from being truly diverse and inclusive; but for now I want to do a quick recap of what I’ve come across over the past week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stephanie-lampkins-blendoorcom&quot;&gt;Stephanie Lampkin’s Blendoor.com&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a goal of reporting on diversity without the influence of unconscious bias, Stephanie created an app last year to report on tech companies workforce makeup.  The app rates companies based on demographics of leadership, retention stats, recruiting practices, bias, and social impact initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An initiative like Blendoor is seriously kick ass.  I am pretty amazed at which companies score higher than others.  Slack is scored lower than Microsoft.  Netflix is scored lower than HP.  I was intrigued that HP has the highest rank out of all scored companies.  There are a lot of companies that don’t have a score yet, and it will be cool to see how this evolves over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blendoor.com/&quot;&gt;Blendoor.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;style--class-vancouver&quot;&gt;Style &amp;amp; Class Vancouver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend and co-worker of mine invited me to attend Style &amp;amp; Class on Wednesday April 12th.  The topic of the Meetup was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/styleandclass/events/238961461/&quot;&gt;Equality &amp;amp; Ideal Futures in Technology&lt;/a&gt;.  I had the honor of hearing Ashley Victoria’s presentation on sexism in the workplace.  From her real-life examples, it’s bewildering to hear how some men view women at work.  How men can behave towards women at work, or at a conference, or at a holiday party.  I was really grateful to hear these stories and to reaffirm, once again, that we can all be an ally to our co-workers and friends - no matter what their makeup or background is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a new week begins, as we see more and more articles in the news around diversity and inclusion, I encourage everyone to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a safe and open environment to discuss these issues at work and at home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to be mindful of what we say and how that might impact how others are viewed or treated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to look for ways to be an ally to those around you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Diversity and inclusion, as a topic, has been very popular in the media lately. From Uber’s ongoing struggles with diversity and culture, and Google being accused of underpaying women employees, you can’t go a week without reading something in the news around these issues.</summary></entry></feed>